A Guide to the Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Inc. records FA085
Rockefeller Archive Center
- DLMA, Inc., 1957-1995; 2; 78.875 Cubic Feet 214 document cases
  - Corporate Records, 2.1
    - Committee Records, 1958-1993; 2.1.3; 5.95 Cubic Feet 13.5 document cases
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, October 26, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 397)
        Report by the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey regarding the proposed People Mover.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, March 3, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 398)
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, July 12, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 399)
        Agenda items include: Seaport Museum Capitol Program; mini-bus service experiment Downtown; updates on the Convention Center and other current projects.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, January 25, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 400)
        Report regarding St. Margaret's House, proposed elderly housing in the Brooklyn Bridge Southwest urban renewal area.
      - Sub-Committee of the Planning Committee - Meeting, May 1, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 401)
      - Sub-Committee of the Planning Committee - Meeting, June 8, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 402)
        Program recommendations and future project list. Meeting of May 26, 1978 rescheduled for June 8, 1978.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, June 30, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 403)
        Discussion of a priority list of future projects.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, August 21, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 404)
        Further discussion of future projects and the priority list. Map with approved or current projects indicated.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, March 1, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 405)
        Oral reports regarding: Transportation Management Study (Vollmer Associates commissioned by the City Planning Commission, the Mayor's Office of Development and the New York City Department of Transportation); Battery Park City (Vollmer Associates on behalf of D-LMA).
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, August 2, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 406)
        Status reports regarding: Battery Park City; Manhattan Community College plans for a new campus on West Street; South Street Seaport; landmarking of lower Broadway; Vista International hotel at the World Trade Center.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, December 11, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 407)
        Review of the new plan for development of Battery Park City (Barbara Moore, Urban Development Corporation).
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, May 6, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 408)
        Updates regarding: Westway; East River development. Meeting of April 10, 1980 cancelled due to transit strike.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, December 11, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 409)
        Agenda items include: "Tall Ships of South STreet" presentation (National Repertory Theatre Foundation); update on Battery Park City and Seaport; Wall Street Park proposal; legalized gambling.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, June 9, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 410)
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, December 7, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 411)
        Report regarding a study of downtown office space. Contains a list of Lower Manhattan reports with summaries, 1958-1978.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, January 13, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 412)
        Discussion of mass transportation and traffic congestion.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, May 12, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 413)
        Mass Transit.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, March 9, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 414)
        Update on Vollmer Associates' Transportation Study. Recommendations for 1983 priorities.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, July 7, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 415)
        Meeting held at 40 West Street, the offices of the Battery Park City Authority. Presentation and tour of the Battery Park City site.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, November 1, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 416)
        Reports regarding: Subway/Development Impact Study (Vollmer Associates); traffic congestion.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, May 30, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 417)
        Report regarding Westway.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, September 20, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 418)
        Discussion includes: Trans Hudson Study (Port Authority of New York and New Jersey); "Journey to Work" Study (Vollmer Associates).
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, February 7, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 419)
        Discussion of subway service to the Water Street area.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, February 20, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 420)
        Report by John Keith and Boris Pushkarev (Regional Plan Association).
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, March 20, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 421)
        Early proposals for the replacement of Westway.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, October 21, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 422)
        Robert Kiley, Chairman, Metropolitan Transportation Authority (MTA), review of phase II of the MTA's 5-year capital program. Water Street Subway Spur - concept paper.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, March 16, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 423)
        Discussion of "Drop-In" Center for the homeless at 38 Beaver Street.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, January 24, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 424)
        Liberty Street Transit Way Design Study proposal.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, February 15, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 425)
        Discussion of the alternatives for Routh 9A.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, June 16, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 426)
        Discussion of the proposed revamping of Battery Park.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, December 6, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 427)
        Review of the D-LMA's recent activities and the progress of the priorities set in 1983.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, September 10, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 428)
        Agenda only.
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, February 13, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 429)
      - Planning Committee - Meeting, January 8, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 430)
      - Public Relations Committee Report - Film on Downtown Program, January 27, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 431)
        "The Downtown Story."
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, March 21, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 432)
        Plans for the D-LMA 10th Anniversary.
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, January 31, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 433)
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, November 30, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 434)
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, February 26, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 435)
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, March 22, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 436)
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, August 24, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 437)
        Convention Center at Battery Park City.
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, April 28, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 438)
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, September 26, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 439)
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, December 5, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 440)
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, November 8, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 441)
        Discussion of a downtown promotion brochure.
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, July 10, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 442)
        Sanitation project.
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, December 19, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 443)
        Anti-litter campaign.
      - Public Relations Committee - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 444)
        Includes: Talk-A-Walk tour of downtown.
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, July 13, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 445)
        Presentation by the publisher of the "New York Gazette," a free periodical distributed Downtown. No affiliation with D-LMA.
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, November 28, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 446)
        Discussion of the slide program "The Other New York" and a proposed downtown documentary film.
      - Public Relations Committee - Meeting, March 28, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 447)
        Plans for the D-LMA's 30th Anniversary and future of the association.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Report, February 23, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 448)
        Hudson & Manhattan Railroad.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Report, June 5, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 449)
        Fulton Street widening.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Report, January 4, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 450)
        West Side site for the World Trade Center.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Report, February 1, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 451)
        Re-survey of Lower Manhattan.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Report, June 29, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 452)
        Progress of re-survey of Lower Manhattan.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, April 18, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 453)
        Recommendations regarding pedestrian and vehicular traffic and parking.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, May 2, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 454)
        Preliminary report on floor space, employment and transportation by Skidmore, Owings and Merrill.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, May 15, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 455)
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Report, May 15, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 456)
        Study to update the "First Report" of October 14, 1958.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, June 6, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 457)
        Discussion of further consideration and future action in the areas of: Land Use, Piers, Traffic, Historic Restoration, Parking.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, December 10, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 458)
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Report, January 24, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 459)
        Survey of rapid transit needs.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, February 20, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 460)
        Presentation of the World Trade Center plan and concept by Port of New York Authority representatives Richard Sullivan and Malcolm Levy.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, February 28, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 461)
        Report and question/answer paper regarding the World Trade Center.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, March 23, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 462)
        Filming of meeting for a WNDT-TV (Channel 13) documentary.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, November 6, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 463)
        Discussion of: City Planning Commission's proposals for the development of the Port of New York; Lower Manhattan Expressway review; East Side Subway proposals.
      - Real Estate Committee - Meeting, November 30, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 464)
        Discussion of Landmarks Preservation Commission bill.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, January 20, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 465)
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, March 29, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 466)
        Discussion includes: the Landmarks Preservation Commission bill; study of Lower Manhattan (City Planning Commission); proposed "Metro City."
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, April 29, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 467)
        Discussion includes: meeting with City Planning Commission; East Side Subway; Landmarks Preservation bill.
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, October 21, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 468)
        Progress reports regarding: East Side Subway study (Coverdale and Colpitts); Lower Manhattan Plan (consultants for the City Planning Commission).
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, November 29, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 469)
        Progress report: East Side Subway study (Coverdale and Colpitts).
      - Real Estate and Traffic and Transportation Committees - Meeting, December 28, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 470)
      - Sanitation - D-LMA Anti-Litter Task Force for On-Street Activities - Organization Meeting, September 29, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 471)
      - Sanitation - D-LMA Anti-Litter Task Force for On-Street Activities - Organization Meeting, October 9, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 472)
      - Sanitation - D-LMA Anti-Litter Task Force for On-Street Activities - Organization Meeting, October 27, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 473)
      - Sanitation - D-LMA Anti-Litter Task Force for On-Street Activities - Organization Meeting, November 3, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 474)
      - Sanitation - Public Relations Committee and Anti-Litter Task Force - Meeting, December 19, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 475)
      - Sanitation - Anti-Litter Task Force - Project Correspondence, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 476)
      - Sanitation - Anti-Litter Task Force - Project Correspondence, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 477)
        RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1081, Box 1, Folder 2.
      - Sanitation - Anti-Litter Task Force - Meeting, March 16, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 478)
        Attendance only.
      - Sanitation - Anti-Litter Task Force - Meeting, June 30, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 479)
        Discussion of the experience to date.
      - Sanitation - Anti-Litter Task Force, November 20, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 480)
      - Sanitation - Anti-Litter Task Force, 1983-1984 (Box 29, Folder 483)
      - D-LMA Task Force Sanitation Committee - Meeting, April 10, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 484)
      - D-LMA Task Force Sanitation Committee - Meeting, September 18, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 485)
      - D-LMA Search Committee - Search for a New Chairman, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 486)
        John E. Zuccotti was elected as Chairman of the D-LMA, October 10, 1990.
      - Sanitation - Anti-Litter Task Force - Logos, 1981-1982 (Box 226, Folder 481)
      - Sanitation - Posters (Box 226, Folder 482)
        "A Great City Deserves Better, Why Litter?" ("We're Cleaning Up Downtown") Posters sponsored by the D-LMA and New York Telephone.
    - Officers' Files, 1958-1995; 2.1.4; 3.525 Cubic Feet 10 document cases
      The files are arranged alphabetically by the last name of the officer and then subdivided chronologically.
      This sub-subseries provides a limited selection of officers' files, mainly encompassing correspondence, for Barbara L. Christen and Justin J. Murphy. Also found in this subseries are David Rockefeller's speech files, which can contain the address given, drafts, related correspondence, and acceptances and denials. Of particular interest are the Directors, Committeepersons, Officers files which provide lists of members of the Board of Directors and various committees, as well as correspondence regarding elections, nominations, appointments, rejections, etc.
      - D-LMA, Inc. - By-Laws (Box 30, Folder 487)
        As amended in 1959, 1971, 1975, 1976, 1977.
      - D-LMA, Inc. - By-Laws (Box 30, Folder 488)
        As amended: 1983 and 1995
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, June 1958-1959 (Box 30, Folder 489)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 490)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 491)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1961-October 1963 (Box 30, Folder 492)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 493)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 494)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 495)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 496)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 0496A)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 497)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 498)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers - Biographical Files, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 499)
        Includes biographies of: Robert S. Curtiss, John B. Goodman, David Rockefeller, Robert C. Tyson, Edmund F. Wagner.
        Portrait of Robert C. Tyson removed. See RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1081, Box 1, Folder 3.
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 500)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 501)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, January-July 1972 (Box 32, Folder 502)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, August-December 1972 (Box 32, Folder 503)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, January-June 1973 (Box 32, Folder 504)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, July-December 1973 (Box 32, Folder 505)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers - Biographical Files, 1973-1974 (Box 32, Folder 506)
        Includes two biographies of Edmund F. Wagner.
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 507)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 508)
        Portraits of David Rockefeller, Justin J. Murphy, Raymond T. O'Keefe, and Edmund F. Wagner removed. See RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1081, Box 1, Folder 4.
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 0508A)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 509)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 510)
        Portrait of Howard L. Clark removed. See RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1081, Box 1, Folder 5.
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 511)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 512)
        Includes biographical files of: Robert R. Douglass and Gordon T. Wallis.
        Portrait of Gordon T. Wallis removed. See RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1081, Box 1, Folder 6.
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 513)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 514)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 515)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 516)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 517)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 518)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 519)
        Includes history of service to the D-LMA for Raymond T. O'Keefe and Edward F. Wagner.
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1987-1989 (Box 33, Folder 520)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1987-1989 (Box 33, Folder 0520A)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 521)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 522)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 523)
      - Directors, Committeepersons, Officers, 1992-1995 (Box 33, Folder 524)
        Includes "DLMA Reports," 1990-1992.
      - Biographical Files - General, 1989-1991 (Box 33, Folder 525)
        Includes resumes and other standard personnel materials.
      - Biographical Files (A-C), 1978-1993 (Box 33, Folder 526)
      - Biographical Files (D-P), 1978-1993 (Box 34, Folder 527)
      - Biographical Files (R-W), 1978-1993 (Box 34, Folder 528)
        Includes resumes and other standard personnel materials. No last names filed under X-Z.
      - Barbara L. Christen - Committees - Notes, 1989-1993 (Box 34, Folder 529)
        Organization, structure, election of committee members, etc.
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 530)
        Christen's "Day File" primarily consists of her outgoing general correspondence with occasional incoming correspondence. In 1988 through June 1989 Christen was Principal of Murry Bergtraum High School.
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, January-June 1989 (Box 34, Folder 531)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, July-December 1989 (Box 34, Folder 532)
        Christen's "Day File" primarily consists of her outgoing general correspondence with occasional incoming correspondence. Barbara L. Christen replaced Justin J. Murphy as President of the D-LMA on July 1, 1989.
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 533)
        Christen's "Day File" primarily consists of her outgoing general correspondence with occasional incoming correspondence.
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, January-June 1991 (Box 34, Folder 534)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, July-December 1991 (Box 35, Folder 535)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, January 1992 (Box 35, Folder 536)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, February 1992 (Box 35, Folder 537)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, March 1992 (Box 35, Folder 538)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, April 1992 (Box 35, Folder 539)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, May 1992 (Box 35, Folder 540)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, June 1992 (Box 35, Folder 541)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, July 1992 (Box 35, Folder 542)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, September 1992 (Box 35, Folder 543)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, October 1992 (Box 35, Folder 544)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, November 1992 (Box 35, Folder 545)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, December 1992 (Box 35, Folder 546)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, January 1993 (Box 35, Folder 547)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, February-March 1993 (Box 35, Folder 548)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, April-May 1993 (Box 35, Folder 549)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, June-July 1993 (Box 35, Folder 550)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, August-September 1993 (Box 36, Folder 551)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, October-December 1993 (Box 36, Folder 552)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, January-June 1994 (Box 36, Folder 553)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, July-December 1994 (Box 36, Folder 554)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Day File, 1995-1996 (Box 36, Folder 555)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Correspondence with Robert R. Douglass, August 1992-July 1993 (Box 37, Folder 556)
        Douglass is D-LMA, Inc. Chairman. Douglass is Vice-Chairman of the Chase Manhattan Bank. Predominantly Christen outgoing correspondence. Additional correspondence with Douglass can be found in the Day File.
      - Barbara L. Christen - Correspondence with Robert R. Douglass, August-December 1993 (Box 37, Folder 557)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Correspondence with Robert R. Douglass, January-May 1994 (Box 37, Folder 558)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Correspondence with Robert R. Douglass, June-December 1994 (Box 37, Folder 559)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Correspondence with Richard Kennedy, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 560)
      - Barbara L. Christen - Correspondence with John E. Zuccotti, 1990-1992 (Box 37, Folder 561)
        President and CEO of Olympia and York Companies. Zuccotti became Chairman of the DLMA in 1990.
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 37, Folder 562)
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 563)
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 564)
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 565)
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 566)
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 567)
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 568)
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 569)
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 570)
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 571)
      - Justin J. Murphy - General Correspondence, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 572)